<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>learning from demonstration on David Paulius, Ph.D. | Personal Website</title>
    <link>https://davidpaulius.github.io/tags/learning-from-demonstration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learning from demonstration on David Paulius, Ph.D. | Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.115.4</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2025 David Paulius</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidpaulius.github.io/tags/learning-from-demonstration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Robot Learning of Assembly Tasks from Non-expert Demonstrations using Functional Object-Oriented Network</title>
      <link>https://davidpaulius.github.io/papers/foon_assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidpaulius.github.io/papers/foon_assembly/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR &amp;ndash; This was a collaboration with Clemson University&amp;rsquo;s Yunyi Jia and Yi Chen, who were interested in using FOONs for representing assembly tasks. They successfully utilized and adapted a FOON to robotic assembly execution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Motion Codes from Demonstration Videos</title>
      <link>https://davidpaulius.github.io/papers/motion_codes_IROS20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidpaulius.github.io/papers/motion_codes_IROS20/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR &amp;ndash; In this work, we showed how motion codes (which can be constructed using the motion taxonomy proposed in our RSS 2020 paper) can be used to improve action recognition with deep neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Motion Taxonomy for Manipulation Embedding</title>
      <link>https://davidpaulius.github.io/papers/motion_codes_RSS20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidpaulius.github.io/papers/motion_codes_RSS20/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR &amp;ndash; In this work, we introduce new changes to the features of the motion taxonomy and show how action verbs encoded as motion codes better capture differences between them than conventional word embedding (as word2vec).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulation Motion Taxonomy and Coding for Robots</title>
      <link>https://davidpaulius.github.io/papers/motion_codes_IROS19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidpaulius.github.io/papers/motion_codes_IROS19/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR &amp;ndash; This paper introduces the motion taxonomy, a collection of robot-relevant features that are better suited for verb or action embedding than conventional word embedding. Motion codes are constructed per verb using the taxonomy. In this work, we show that motion codes assigned to verbs are closely related to one another based on force and trajectory data.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
